{"tossups": [{"question": "While working for this newspaper, Bryan Burrough and John Helyar covered the acquisition of RJR Nabisco by KKR in<em> Barbarians at the Gate</em>. This newspaper originally coined the phrase \u201clucky duckies\u201dto describe Americans below the income tax line. Along with the Heritage Foundation, this newspaper publishes the<em> Index of Economic Freedom</em>.<em> Den of Thieves, 24 Days,</em> and<em> Bad Blood</em> were all books expanded from expos\u00b4es conducted by this newspaper, published by Dow Jones & Co. For the point, name this business-centric U.S. newspaper headquartered in New York City.", "answer": "The<em><b> Wall Street Journal</b></em> (prompt on a partial answer, accept The<b> W.S.J.</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This museum\u2019s holdings began from a collection assembled by Johann Gotzkowski which was refused by Frederick the Great. The original building to house this museum was designed by Jean Baptiste de la Motte as an extension to a larger building which contained the Gold and Malachite Drawing Rooms and which is nowadays also part of this museum. Works from this museum were evacuated by train to Sverdlovsk before a 1941 siege of this museum\u2019s city. Catherine the Great started, for the point, what museum which includes the Winter Palace in Saint Petersburg?", "answer": "The<b> Hermitage</b> (prompt on Winter Palace until mention)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "During this period, Sugawara Michizane, a renowned expert in<em> kanshi</em> and<em> waka</em> poetry, helped settle the Ako Incident in favor of Emperor Uda. This period\u2019s Hogen Disturbance resulted in Go-Shirakawa\u2019s abdication to a Buddhist monastery as a \u201ccloistered emperor\u201d. The acquisition of<em> shoen</em> estates by the Fujiwara clan during this period contributed to the growing power of the samurai. The Minamoto brought an end to this period by defeating the Taira in the Genpei War. The Kamakura shogunate replaced, for the point, what relatively peaceful period of Japanese history named for a previous name of Kyoto?", "answer": "<b> Heian</b> Period", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Zechariah Chafee criticized this man\u2019s decision in a case later upheld by<em> Whitney v. California</em>. This man wrote that the \u201clife of the law has not been logic but experience\u201d in his 1881 book,<em> The Common</em> <em>Law</em>. One of this justice\u2019s famous dissents invoked freedom of contracts and Spencer\u2019s<em> Social Statics</em> to illustrate limitations of the Fourteenth Amendment in<em> Lochner v. New York</em>. The \u201cclear and present danger\u201d test was advocated by, for the point, what Supreme Court Justice who wrote the unanimous opinion in<em> Schenck v. U.S</em>?", "answer": "Oliver Wendell<b> Holmes</b> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Prior to this conflict, one ruler sent the Letters from the Segovia Woods, refusing to relax persecution of Protestants. Calvinists were granted concessions by Margaret of Parma in an attempt to prevent this conflict, but she was replaced by a leader who failed to suppress this conflict with the Councils of Blood, the Duke of Alba. The Pacification of Ghent united one side after Antwerp was sacked during this conflict. William the Silent helped start, for the point, what long revolt against Spanish rule which created the United Provinces in the modern-day Netherlands?", "answer": "<b> 80 Years\u2019</b> War (accept the<b> Dutch Revolt</b>, accept the<b> Dutch War of Independence</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "John Filson named this city \u201cLosaintville\u201d, which is comprised of words from four languages. Arthur St. Clair changed this city\u2019s name to reference an organization founded by Henry Knox that preserved the fellowship of officers in the Continental Army. This \u201cCity of the Seven Hills\u201d not located in Illinois was a pork processing city known as \u201cPorkopolis\u201d. After Columbus and Cleveland, for the point, name this third largest city in Ohio.", "answer": "<b> Cincinnati</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "These people formed communities in West Africa where they were called<em> agud\u00b4as</em> due to their western culture. Ganga Zumba led a kingdom of these people which included the Great and Little Palmares. Muslim ones of these people rose up during the Male [mah-lay] Revolt in Bahia, where most of these people arrived. These people formed fugitive settlements called<em> quilombos</em>. Children of these people were helped by the 1871 Law of Free Birth. The Golden Law freed, for the point, what forced laborers who worked on coffee and sugar plantations in a Portuguese colony?", "answer": "<b> Brazil</b>ian<b> slaves</b> (prompt on a partial answer)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "While serving in this position, Arthur Summerfield experimented with missile-based transportation and created the Hamper-Dumper sorting system. In 1971, this position was rolled into a new federal agency causing Winton Blount to be its last holder that was part of the Cabinet. The holder of this office oversees an agency that operates Grumman LLVs and organizes Rural Free Delivery. Benjamin Franklin was the first holder of, for the point, what position in charge of facilitating mail delivery?", "answer": "<b> Postmaster General</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Arthur Hays led an investigation into a police shooting at a Cadets of the Republic march in this region, whose then-governor Blanton Winship was not prosecuted for the Ponce Massacre. This region\u2019s economy was industrialized by Operation Bootstrap. Displaying this region\u2019s flag was banned by the Gag Law, unrest from which culminated in the Utuado and Jayuya Uprisings. The Foraker Act was replaced by the Jones-Shafroth Act, which granted US citizenship to people born in this region. For the point, name this US commonwealth territory governed from San Juan.", "answer": "Commonwealth of<b> Puerto Rico</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A mayor in this country declared \u201cI determine who is a Jew!\u201d and constantly attacked his Jewish opponent Victor Adler. A leader of this country was called \u201cshorty\u201d for his stiff leg after being appointed Reichskomissar of the Netherlands. Kurt Schuschnigg failed to deter one takeover of this country after the July Putsch assassinated his predecessor, Engelbert Dollfuss. Arthur Seyss-Inquart was promoted to Chancellor after the Nazis forced this country to accept one union. For the point, name this country where Hitler was born near Linz, which was annexed in the Anschluss.", "answer": "<b> Austria</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name this Democratic nominee twice beaten by Eisenhower.", "answer": "Adlai E.<b> Stevenson</b> II", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "People unable to pay the dakapati or water tax in this modern-day country were instead forced to repair the water reservoirs. The Mahavamsa records the arrival of Asoka\u2019s son Mahinda to this modern-day country and King Devanampiya Tissa\u2019s subsequent conversion to Buddhism. Failing irrigation tanks triggered the Great Famine in this country\u2019s Anuradhapura Kingdom, which fell to Chola invasions. Sangam literature, which was primarily composed in the Tamil language, originated in, for the point, what island country formerly known as Ceylon?", "answer": "<b> Sri Lanka</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "These people dealt a decisive blow to Berenger I of Italy at the Battle of Brenta by feigning a retreat. Dual rulers of these people were known as the kende and the gyula. These people migrated from Etelkoz after facing Pecheneg incursions. Conrad the Red betrayed these people during a battle where Conrad died while reinforcing his Swabian allies. These people, who were ruled by the Arpad dynasty, lost a 955 battle to Otto the Great at the plains of Lechfeld. For the point, name this ethnic group that invaded central Europe during the Middle Ages, ultimately settling in modern-day Hungary.", "answer": "<b> Magyar</b>s (prompt on Hungarians before \u201cHungary\u201d is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "One hostage event in this city resulted in the deaths of the American ambassador and the Belgian <em>charg\u00b4e d\u2019affaires</em> after the Black September Organization seized this city\u2019s Saudi Embassy in 1973. This city\u2019s al-Shifa factory was targeted by US cruise missiles in retaliation for this city\u2019s supposed harboring of bin Laden from 1991 to 1996. William Gladstone\u2019s government was blamed for its defeat in one siege of this city which resulted in the death of Charles \u201cChinese\u201d Gordon. For the point, name this capital city of Sudan, located at the confluence of the Blue and White Niles.", "answer": "<b> Khartoum</b> or<b> al-Khartum</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man formulated a namesake doctrine which held that the federal government had not power to limit slavery as it deprived the people to their right to property. In his<em> A Disquisition on Government</em>, this man outlined his belief of \u201cconcurrent majority\u201d as a way to protect the subjugated South. On his deathbed, Andrew Jackson regretted that he had not executed this man, his former Vice President, for treason. Nullification was developed by, for the point, what South Carolina politician?", "answer": "John Caldwell<b> Calhoun</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The first of one of these events began after the Antideficiency Act under Comptroller General Elmer Staats\u2019s purview had its interpretation changed by Benjamin Civetti. That event in 1980 forced federal marshals to close FTC offices. Newt Gingrich caused several of these events under Bill Clinton while another occurred when Heritage Action and senators like Ted Cruz opposed Obamacare. The Mexico border wall has caused, for the point, what type of event that causes some federal employees to go on furlough because the government failed to pass a budget?", "answer": "Federal Government<b> Shutdown</b> in the United States", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This politician\u2019s son George Washington drowned in the Long Island Sound after possibly jumping off the<em> Benjamin Franklin</em>. Due to his constant petitions against slavery, this man was the chief target of an 1836 gag rule which was eventually repealed in 1844. This man negotiated the acquisition of Florida with Luis de Onis in his role as James Monroe\u2019s Secretary of State. For the point, name this career politician who returned to Congress after serving as 6th President of the United States.", "answer": "<b> J</b>ohn<b> Q</b>uincy<b> Adams</b> (prompt on Adams; do not accept or prompt on John Adams)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Desborough Committee was created to review these people, who struck in 1919. Before the Macdaniel Scandal, \u201cthief-takers\u201d took on the role of these people, who fought two Latvian revolutionaries in the Siege of Sidney Street. Henry Fielding formed the first professional group of these people, the Bow Street Runners. These people\u2019s ineptitude was mocked in Punch cartoon,\u201cBlind man\u2019s buff,\u201d where one of these people fails to find for Jack the Ripper. For the point, name these people who may serve in a Metropolitan version headquartered at Scotland Yard to stop crime.", "answer": "<b> Police</b> men/women (accept<b> Liverpool Police</b> or<b> London Police</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}